### Trisha N. Patel

#### **Behavioral Scientist and Data Analyst**

(408) 230-5351 tpatel65@illinois.edu LinkedIn

Ph.D. Candidate in Cognitive Psychology with a B.A. in Data Analysis and 2 years of professional experience in Fortune 100, looking to build on research and technical skills.

#### Education

#### University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign (2015-2020)

Ph.D. in Psychology – Cognitive Science (expected Fall 2020, GPA: 3.94)
M.A. in Psychology – Cognitive Science Division (2017, GPA: 4.0)

## University of California, Santa Cruz (2011- 2015)

Summa cum laude (GPA: 3.98) B.S. in Cognitive Science B.A. in Data Analysis

#### **Honors and Awards**

- Outstanding Researcher (2015)
- Outstanding Scholar (2015)
- Frank X. Barron Memorial Award in Creativity Research (2013)

#### Research Skills

- Experimental Design
- Data Collection and Analysis
- Big Data Machine Learning and Observational Studies

#### **Programming Languages**

R, Python, MATLAB, Javascript

#### Teaching Experience

- Cognitive Psychology
- Learning and Memory
- Sensation and Perception
- Data Analysis
- Pre-Calculus
- Social Networks

#### **Data Analysis and Research Experience**

#### AbbVie Innovation Center at Research Park

2018-Present

#### Statistical Analyst for HEOR

Using real-world big data to assess the impact of AbbVie products on payers, providers, and patients. Programming completed in R.

# University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign Cognitive Division

2015-Present

#### Ph.D. Candidate in Cognitive Psychology

Designed and developed online, interactive research for areas in perception, memory, and attention. Led studies that implemented computational models for cognitive processing using R and Python.

#### National Center for Professional Research and Ethics

#### **Project Associate**

Developed an application using R Shiny to identify solutions for common problems occurring in professional settings.

#### University of California, Santa Cruz Learning and Memory Laboratory

2012-2015

2017-2018

#### Research Assistant under Benjamin Storm, Ph.D.

Designed, analyzed, and published research addressing the adaptive processes of forgetting.

#### University of California, Santa Cruz Learning Support Services

2013-2015

#### Program Coordinator for College Algebra.

Developed and gained funds to research the effectiveness of the UCSC math tutor program. Implemented data analysis methods using R and SPSS. Research informed changes to the university math program.

#### NASA Ames: Summer Internship Advanced Studies Laboratory

2014

# Research Intern at the Exploration Technology Human Systems Integration division of the Spatial Auditory Displays Lab.

Facilitated research for the development of spacesuits for exploration of Mars. Furthered data collection and analysis using SPSS and MATLAB. Furthered the design of spacesuits and habitation of planets.

## University of Rochester: Summer Internship Center for Vision Science

2013

Research Fellow under the supervision of Benjamin Hayden, PhD. Advanced research in the neurobiology of decision making in rhesus monkeys. Programming completed in MATLAB.

#### Journal Publications

- Monitoring the ebb and flow of attention: Does controlling the onset of stimuli during encoding enhance memory?
- Exploring the Contribution of Spatial and Non-Spatial Working Memory to Priming of Pop-Out.
- Forgetting as a consequence and enabler of creative thinking.